ANTON SMIRNOV

Summary

I'm a Front End Web Developer with an emphasis on React and experience in small web production projects and a startup doing sites for local clients. I am a motivated and energetic individual who likes to solve tricky problems and resolve code bugs. Passionate about producing great user experiences with a customer-first attitude. During my last assignment role, I helped the company stay organized and save up to 21% of productive time, which translated into an additional 77% of revenue for the company and up to 80% for the clients.

Projects

May 2020 to Current Burger Builder

Stack: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Redux, Redux Saga, Firebase

Implemented class-based code for React.

Connected Redux for state management.

Used Redux Saga to perform side-effects for the application.

Replaced class-based code with React Hooks.

Used custom axios, and interceptors to chance state

Used React.lazy to lazily import some components.

Created a custom React Hook to handle errors in Request.

Used React, memo and useCallback for performance optimization.

Google Firebase as a backend replacement and realtime database.

Was deployed both on Firebase and Netlify.

A user can log in, signup, add ingredients, see the total price, orders, and make orders.

Mobile-friendly application.

JavaScript Games Apr. 2020

Stack: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Building popular legendary games on vanilla JavaScipt.

Added new classes, updated innerHTML content based on the final result.

Applied setAttribute, getAttributeApplied, setInterval, clearInterval, addEventListener to add and manage content of the game.

Used e.keyCode to manage the direction of the snake.

Ticketing4Good Mar 2020

Stack: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, Material UI, Bootstrap, PostreSQL, NodeMailer, Node.js

Used React Hooks for the front-end part. Learnt Material UI in two weeks to design components.

Used Bootstrap to manage different alert types.

Used NodeMailer to send emails.

Used Stripe technology to process payments.

Used QRcode to create QR codes and insert those ones into tickets.

Applied Google Maps API to locate events on the map

A user can watch and search for events, can see a description of those events.

A user can buy tickets for those events and add them to a cart, can update the cart.

A user can go to a checkout page and make a payment.

Once the payment is successful the user will get an email with all the information plus a ticket with a QR code for the event.

Mar. 2020 Article on medium Understanding Closures in JavaScript

Feb. 2020 Article on medium Prototype Inheritance

Jan. 2020 Stack: HTML, SASS, JS, iQuery, AJAX, NodeJS, Express

Tweeter is a simple, SPA Twitter clone

URL shortener Jan. 2020 Stack: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, NodeJS, Express, EJS

URL shortener is a full-stack web application built with Node and Express that allows users to shorten long URLs

Stack: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, Bitrix

Mobile friendly site

Visitor can order a returning call

Visitor can see, read articles based on categories chosen

A few thousands of visitors every 24hrs

June 2019 Apartment repair

Stack: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery Mobile friendly site

Visitor can order a returning call, check examples of work

Lawyer Ovsyankin May 2019

Stack: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, iOuery

Mobile friendly site

Visitor can order a returning call, leave feedback Site for a local lawyer

Apr. 2019 5 ria add

Stack: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery

Mobile friendly site Visitor can order a returning call

Advertisement site for a local client

Master for an hour Mar. 2019 Stack: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery

Mobile friendly site

Visitor can order a returning call

A site to find professionals such as plumbers, electricians, etc.

Contact

antosha19851985@gmail.com

+1(306)2505861

♥ Montreal, Ouebec, Canada

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/as8/

O https://github.com/antosha-85

Skills

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

JavaScrint

HTML5

CSS3

Ruby

FRAMEWORKS AND ENVIRONMENT

NodelS

jQuery

Express

Webpack Bootstran

Ruby on Rails Material UI

Redux

DATABASES AND CMC

PostgreSQL

Git Firehase

TESTING Mocha

Chai

Cypress

Storybook

Enzvme

CLOUD APPLICATION PLATFORM

Heroku

Netlify

LANGUAGES English

Russian

Online

July 2019

Education

LighthouseLabs Jan. 2020 to Apr. 2020 Web Development Diploma Calgary. AB Full Stack Web Developer

Web Development Bootcamp on June 2019 to Dec. Üdemy

Jan. 2019 to June 2019 HTML academy HTML Academy Certificate Online Front End

Tyumen State Oil and Gas University · Sept. 2002 to June June 2007 2007

Diploma with honors

Master's Degree Petroleum Engineering, Russia

Employment

Freelancer

Apr. 2020 to Current

Worked on personal and freelance projects using Agile Principles as a Front End Web Developer Stack - HTML, CSS, Less, JavaScript, JQuery, Twig, Behat, React, Redux,

Ganin Incorporation

Surgut, Russia Feb. 2019 to Aug. 2019

Worked in a team of two developers (myself and a senior full-stack developer) using Agile Principles, such as scrum meetings and weekly or biweekly review sessions, which helped company stay organized and save up to 21% of productive time

Worked on the front end of multiple sites, was recognized by the owner and clients, which translated into an additional 77% of revenue for the company and up to 80% for the clients Stack - HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, iOuery, Bitrix

Phoenix Technology Service

Calgary, Canada Aug. 2018 to Dec. 2019

Was recognized by a client representative on 2 occasions Had 0 NPT and 0 HSE incidents

Schlumberger Logelco Inc.

Tyumen, Russia Aug. 2017 to May 2018

Used Python integrated into the software to perform logical tasks and calculations

Worked using Agile Principles such as had daily scrum meetings, weekly or biweekly review sessions

Was responsible for a new project and presented one to potential clients

Tyumen, Russia Oct. 2014 to July 2017 **Operations Support Engineer**

Supported more than 30 jobs simultaneously in real-time from the Operation Support Center (OSC)

Led Service Quality Meetings on a monthly basis, and learning sessions for junior engineers, which reduced NPT by 18%

Mentored 5+ people

Russia, China, UAE Aug. 2010 to Sept. 2014 MLWD Engineer

Finished Global Project Working Instructions in 6 months

Surgutneftegaz Oil and Gas production operator Surgut, Russia July 2007 to July 2007

Participated in a conference of new technologies as a program for young specialists

Awards

Tyumen State Oil and Gas University · Won a competition in mechanics among all the branches of my university

Oct. 2003

References

Canadian references are available upon request.